Tremaine Shelton

Software Engineer

Buffalo NY, 14213

Tremained.shelton@gmail.com

Contact: 714-499-8213

Summary

SOFTWARE ENGINEERING

Software developer with 4+ years of professional experience in designing, developing, and delivering
user-centric software applications utilizing Java/J2EE technologies. Candidate proactive as a team
member working in Agile environments with strong skills frontend and backend development, both
server-side and client-side technologies.

Technical Skills

Languages	Core Java, Java, J2EE, SQL, C/C++, Python
Java/J2EE Technologies	Servlets, JSP, Java Database Connection (JDBC)
Java Frameworks	Spring, Spring Boot, Hibernate
Web Servers	Apache, Tomcat
Version Control Tools	GIT, Git Hub
Web Technologies	HTML5, XML, CSS, JavaScript, jQuery, Angular
Operating Systems	Windows, Linux/UNIX, Mac OS
Testing Tools	JUnit
Databases/Tools	Oracle, MySQL, SQL
Build Tools	Maven
Methodologies	Agile, Waterfall
Cloud Computing	AWS, EBS, EC2, S3, RDS
Logging Tools	Log4j

Professional Experience

Cognizant Technologies

July 2022 - October 2023

Role: Software Engineer – Java Developer

Responsibilities -

- Responsible for development and sustainability architecture for e-commerce applications utilizing both front-end and back-end technologies such as Java, SpringBoot, SQL, Javascript, AWS.
- Participated in Agile [SCRUM] meetings with teams and triaging with third-party vendors.
- Used JavaScript for client-side validations in the JSP and HTML pages, as well as to design and form user registration layouts.
- Worked with updating components and utilized Core Java methods in code-base environment.
- Experienced in AWS Clouds services to work with containers and Spring dependency injections as well.
- Utilized SQL technologies for creating and adding database queries and CRUD operations.
- Documented work and updates via Confluence page for tutorials, diagrams, and flowcharts for peer developers and IT for guidance or FAQ.
- Collaborated with other developers on designing, developing, testing, and implementing new web features, HTML pages, and documentation updating and presenting.
- Implemented new features and resolved bugs and user account errors and exceptions handling.
- Participated in peer-reviews and development with teammates for solution designs and related code.
- Splunk admin troubleshooting experience to diagnose the root of failure for Dashboards and Data onboarding via index and field extraction per user error.
- Worked with integration of Amazon Web Services with other applications infrastructure.
- Wrote and maintained build scripts for E2Open cloud platform SaaS applications modules like supplier services and admin portal using Maven.
- Worked with Third-party applications and clients in meetings and reports for any updates or ideas brought of development team, triage is called if error depending on what third-party application is.

ClassBoxes Technologies

Jan 2019- June 2022

Role: Consultant - Java Software Developer Responsibilities -

- Worked with the development of E-commerce applications for banking clients.
- Built Java web applications utilizing HTML, CSS, Angular, Node.js, Core Java, SpringBoot, RestAPI and AWS Cloud technologies.
- Created and innovated flow chart documentation for peer developers in Confluence pages.

- Backend development using Spring, SpringBoot, Rest API, and AWS Cloud services.
- Front-end development using technologies such as Html, CSS, and Angular to create page layouts and features for e-commerce-based applications.
- Communicated with third-party vendors and applications any updates or issues with programs and established triage calls across directories in Confluence pages.
- Familiarity with codebase and running test, scripts, building and working with pipelines such as Jenkins.
- Working with Rest Api's consumption task and CRUD operations for client or user request.
- Building and testing layouts for web applications and pages.
- Creating Admin dashboards and marketing dashboards for clients increasing marketing rep sales for users registered, and the number of user submissions made.
- Working with API tokens for admin authentication and cloud services.

LCP Tracker

September 2018 – January 2019

Role: Technical Support Specialist

Responsibilities -

- Assisted customers and clients with how to use UI on application.
- Worked with payroll software application which assisted clients with tracking their payroll data.
- Attention to detail when assisting and performing mathematical calculations to ensure payment and information is correct.
- Escalating certain designated issues to tier 2 support when necessary and utilizing Salesforce.
- Run computer maintenance (Virus scans, Malware checks, Updates, Disk checks, Defragment)
- Troubleshooting computers to fix Hardware/Software issues.
- Install new software and peripheral devices, such as monitors and keyboards, as well as motherboards and Hard drives as needed.
- Responding quickly, courteously, discreetly and accurately by phone, fax or mail.

Education

Computer Software Certification - Advanced Software Development

University at Phoenix - Completed Certification C/o 2022

Bachelors in Science, Criminal Justice

State University of New York at Fredonia – Graduated C/o 2018